（左慈(さじ)）チッ…
You bastards... are too cocky.
（左慈）
調子に乗り過ぎだよ 貴様ら
Th... This is Zuoci?!
（壁(へき)）こ… これが 左慈か！
クッ… 何をしている…
What am I doing?
As our leader, now's the most important time...
今こそ
隊を率いる私がヤツの前に出て
味方の士気を高めるとき
for me to step out in front of him to boost our morale!
But... even knowing that... my body won't move.
だが 分かっていても 体が動かぬ…
It just won't!
動かぬ！
Hey, hey.
（信(しん)）おいおい
お前(めえ)こそ 調子に乗り過ぎだよ
You're the one who's too cocky!
まぬけヅラ！
With that stupid face of yours!
Xin!
（壁）信！
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years...
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Qpax
Now's the only time.
～♪
The Ultimate Blade
（兵士たち）ウワッ！
（刺す音）
（兵士）ウワッ！
（政(せい)）トーッ！
（楊端和(ようたんわ)）さすが秦王
自ら乱戦に向かっていくか
Just what I've come to expect, King of Qin.
You're delving into the melee on your own?
Have you felt that presence?
（戦士）気配がしませんか？
（楊端和）うん？
Is it Bajiou?
（戦士）バジオウですか？
（楊端和）いや 恐らく あの少年だ
No... Most likely, it's that boy.
It looks like the crucial time has finally come over there as well!
向こうも
いよいよ時が満ちたようだ
You're the one who's too cocky, moron!
調子に乗り過ぎだよ ボケ！
Ah?
“ああ？”じゃねえよ！ こらー！
Screw you, asshole!
ウッ… いってえ…
Ow...
You're pretty quick, ya bastard.
速(はえ)えな この野郎
ぶっ殺す！
I'll kill you!
トリャー！
（兵士）な… 何だ？ あのガキは
Wh-What is that kid?
いつも
一刀でしとめる左慈さまと…
Zuoci is the man who always finished people in one stroke,
but that boy's standing against him!
打ち合ってやがる！
Awesome...
（貂(てん)）すげえ…
信 頑張れ
Xin... Keep it up.
おら！
なぜだ… 信…
How... Xin?
How is it that even though you're just a boy, you can fight against Zuoci?!
（壁）なぜ 少年の君が
左慈を相手に立ち向かえるんだ？
Aren't you afraid?
恐ろしくないのか？
Where the hell you two hiding that kind of power?
君たちは 一体
どこに そんな力を秘めている？
ハッ… “君たち”？
You two...?
Lord Piao...
漂(ひょう)どの…
That's it. Lord Piao took the lead unflinchingly and cut through the Wang Qi army's forces.
そうだ
漂どのも あの王騎(おうき)軍を相手に―
ひるむことなく先頭を切り進んだ
What the hell are you two...?
君たちは 一体…
I'm going to be the greatest general under the heavens!
（信）
俺は天下の大将軍になるんだ！
The greatest general under the heavens?
（壁）“天下の大将軍”？
これはまた途方もない夢だな
That's and enormous dream, too!
For someone so stupid,
（貂）こいつ バカのわりに
夢と態度だけは でっかいんだよな
his dreams and his ego are huge!
つい この間まで―
Just the other day he was racking his brain over if he could become a general...
どうやったら将軍になれるのかも
知らなかったド平民のくせに
even though he's a bottom-rank commoner!
Sheddep!
（信）
うるせえ！ なるったら なるんだ！
I said I'll become it and I will!
それに こいつは
俺１人の夢じゃないからな
And also...
this isn't just my dream alone!
It's a perilous path!
（政）険しい道だぞ
フン… 上等じゃねえか！
どんな道だろうと 俺は…
I'm just fine with that!
No matter what kinda path it is, I'll...
おっとっと！
（政）だから 言っただろう
“険しい道だ”と
It's like he said, a perilous path.
（信）て… てめえ… ふざけんな
Y-You bastard,
don't screw with me!
将軍への道の険しさは
こんなものでは ないぞ
Compared to the peril of the path to being a general, what we're doing today is nothing.
フン… 望むところだ
All right then...
あと ひとつ言っておくが
ただの将軍じゃねえ
But make sure you get it, I'm not gonna be just a general.
“天下の大将軍”だ！
The greatest! General! Under! The Heavens!
Don't screw it up!
間違えるんじゃねえ！
（政）そうだな
Yeah, right.
Yup!
（信）あっ… 政 てめえ
今 バカにしただろう！
Zheng, you bastard!
Were you just making fun of me?!
くそ！ 見てろ
絶対 なってやるからな！
Shit! Just watch me! I'm definitely gonna become it!
Can you... really become it... Xin?
（壁）
本当になるというのか？ 信…
If you can...
だとしたら…
ドリャー！
You, a nameless servant boy... becoming the greatest general under the heavens...
（壁）名もない下僕の身の君が
天下の大将軍に…
If that happens...!
だとしたら…
Fuck yeah!
（信）
よっしゃ 当たった！ ざまあみろ！
I hit ya! How's that, bastard?!
This fight's only just beginning!
こっからが勝負だぜ
（兵士）お… おい…
（兵士）あ… ああ…
H-Hey...
Hey, hey! What're ya spacing out for?!
おらおら 何ボケッとしてんだよ
ビビっちまったのか？
Ya ain't scared, are ya?!
な… 何だ？ 今の
全く見えなかった…
Wh-What was that...?
I couldn't see it at all...
信！
Xin!
Xin... If you really do become a great general...
（壁）信 君が
本当に大将軍になるのだとしたら…
君は 中華統一を
目指す大王の片腕となって―
You'd be the right hand of the king who's aiming to unite all of China...
and fly all over the world...
天下に羽ばたく！
だとしたら…
Then...
Then...!
だとしたら！
（左慈）逝(い)け
Die.
I've already let one die.
（壁）私は既に１人 死なせている
この少年は 絶対に殺させぬ！
But I'll never let this boy be killed!
This one's shallow, too. But I cut him twice.
これも浅い …が ２度 斬った！
もう１歩 踏み込めば 取れる！
If I can get one step further, I can kill him!
Biiiii!
壁ーっ！
フゥ… 続きだ 小僧
Let's continue, kid.
（斬る音）
（兵士）ウワッ！
Are you all right, my king?!
（兵士）大王！ 大丈夫ですか？
It's nothing.
かまうな
この程度 かすり傷にも入らぬ
You couldn't even call this a scratch.
（兵士１）
しかし 中に入り過ぎです
But you're too deep into the fray!
大王は 我らのあとに…
My king, you should get behind...
Prepare yourself... king.
（魏興(ぎこう)）大王 お覚悟
Weixing...
魏興…
ハァ… ハァ…
てめえ… よくも壁を…
Bastard... How could you do that to Bi...?!
なに？
頭に食らった一撃のせいか？
What?! Is it because of the one attack I took to the head?!
The sword is strength!
“剣は力”
The sword is speed!
“剣は速さ”
信！
Xin!
My strength is...
力が…
共に最上を極める この俺は…
To have reached the highest level with it, I am...
天下最強だ
the strongest under the heavens.
Hey, kid.
（左慈）おい 小僧
そんな左慈さまに傷をつけたな
You harmed Lord Zuoci quite a bit, didn't you?
So how are you going to pay for that?
どう落とし前つけてくれるんだ？
お前　ああ？
Like I thought... Lord Zuoci has completely snapped.
やはり 左慈さま 完全にキレてるぞ
Of course.
当たり前だ　服を汚されただけで
相手を真っ二つにするお方だ
This is the man who cuts a person in half just for dirtying his clothes.
あのガキ なぶり殺しにされるぞ
That kid... He's gonna be tortured to death.
…だな
そして これで勝負は決した
Yeah... And the bout is settled now.
いくぞ！
（兵士）皆殺しだ！
Let's go!
We'll kill them all!
He's alive!
生きてる！
（斬る音）
（兵士）グワッ！
（貂）壁！ しっかりしろ 壁！
Bi! Get a hold of yourself! Bi!
えっ？ 何だ？ 何か言ったか？
What?
Did you say something?
How is... the battle?
（壁）戦況は？
Everyone's in tough fights...
みんな 苦戦してる…
Especially Xin...
特に 信は…
戦況は すごく不利だよ すごく…
We're... at a really bad disadvantage.
Really...
でも 大丈夫だ！
だって こっちには信がいる！
But it'll be okay!
Because we have Xin!
No matter how beat up he gets, he never loses.
あいつは どんなに
ボロボロになっても負けやしない
どんなにボロボロになっても…
No matter how bad it is...
He'll definitely win!
絶対 勝つ！
Isn't that right, Xin?!
そうだろう？ 信！
（兵士）エイッ！ おら！
（信）グワッ！
Hey, hey. Who said it's okay to sit down?
おいおい
誰が しゃがんでいいと言った？
立たんか こら！
Can't you stand, bastard?!
What's wrong? You guys formed a separate squadron to attack the inner palace, right?
どうした？ 貴様ら別動隊となって
本殿を討つ算段だったのだろう？
Then give it a try!
ならば 行ってみよ！
この俺を倒して！
Defeat me!
What's wrong, kid? Huh?
どうした？
小僧 どうした！ 早く立たんか！
Why don't you stand up already?!
C'mon! C'mon!
もう終わりか？ おらおらおら！
Finished already?
C'mon! C'mon! C'mon!
し… 信…
X... Xin...
信！
Xiiiiin!
（信）来た！
（左慈）おらー！
There it is.
（信）ケッ… バカが！
長々と しゃべりやがって
You idiot.
Blabbering on like that...
I didn't hear a damn word you said, so I'll need you to say it one more time.
全然 聞いてなかったから
もう一度 言ってくれよ
誰が天下最強だって？
Who the fuck's the strongest under the heavens?!
Thanks to your idle chatter, I'm totally back to normal.
てめえの与太話のおかげで
すっかり元に戻っちまったぜ
Now, stand up.
さあ 立てよ
I'll teach you who's the strongest under the heavens!
誰が天下最強か教えてやる！
（魏興）ほう… その若さで―
Oh? Despite being so young,
he's able to stand before me, unflinchingly, while I'm mounted on my horse?
騎馬した この魏興を前に
ひるまぬとは…
Even though he's in the royal family, he has the heart of a warrior!
王族ながら武心(ぶしん)が宿るか！
Perhaps this is the second coming of King Zhao.
あるいは 昭王(しょうおう)の再来か…
But!
だが 生まれ落ちた時と場所が
悪すぎたな！
The time and place you were born in were simply too unfortunate!
Forgive me!
御免！
何だ？
What?!
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）馬上に
ふんぞり返っとるわりには…
Having gotten so arrogant up on that horse,
your sword has gotten quite a bit lighter, Weixing.
随分と軽い剣だな 魏興
昌文君！
Changwenjun!
Until the separate squadron has reached the inner palace...
別動隊が本殿にたどりつくまで…
Until we strike down Chengjiao and Jie Shi...!
（昌文君）
成蟜(せいきょう)と竭氏(けつし)を討ち取るまで…
No matter what it takes, we must hold out here!
（政）
なんとしても ここは耐えしのぐ！
I'm counting on you, Xin!
頼んだぞ 信！
（王騎）
相変わらず渋いですね 昌文君は
That Changwenjun is glum as usual...
しかし １か所 見物できないことが
残念ですねえ
It's too bad I can't see what's going on in one area, though.
Are you there, Teng?
騰(とう)は いますか？
（騰）はっ！ お呼びでしょうか？
Yes. You called?
あちらの回廊の様子を
見てきてもらえますか？
Could you take a look at the state of things in the corridor over there?
おい 誰か 右龍(うりゅう)へ…
（王騎）あなたに言ってますよ 騰
Hey, someone check the Youlong...
I'm telling you to, Teng.
しかし
あそこは左慈が守っているはず
But Zuoci should be guarding that place.
The separate squadron is surely already wiped out.
既に別動隊は全滅しているのでは？
（王騎）あの回廊を抜けたら
本殿までは阻むものはありません
If they make it through that corridor...
there will be nothing blocking them to get to the inner palace.
肆氏(しし)は必勝を期して
左慈を配置したのでしょうねえ
Jie Shi must have placed Zuoci there expecting certain victory.
しかし それを承知で 王と昌文君は
別動隊を送ったのですよ
But knowing that, the king and Changwenjun sent a separate force inside.
左慈を抜く自信があると？
You're saying they're confident they can get past Zuoci?!
Who knows...
さあ？ 自信があるかは さておき…
Setting aside whether they're confident or not...
You can be sure that the two who hold the greatest amount of trust are fighting in there.
あそこでは
２人が最も信頼を寄せている者が
戦っているということで
間違いないでしょう フフフフッ…
I see...
そうか…
遊んでいるうちに回復したか
You recovered while I was playing around...?
So what?
だから どうした？
結局は最初に戻っただけだ
All we've done is go back to the beginning.
You no longer have a mask to protect your head.
もう頭を守る面は ないぞ
次の一刀で
少ない脳みそをぶちまけてやろう
With my next strike, I'll smash a little bit of your brain.
That's right. One strike...
そう 一刀だ
チッ…
あちこち斬られて 血を流し過ぎた
I've lost too much blood from being cut all over...
感覚のねえとこが
ちらほら ありやがる
And I've got some places here and there where I can't feel anything...
余力は一刀のみ…
I've only got strength for one slash.
But that's plenty!
だが それで十分だ
これは木刀じゃねえ
This isn't a wooden sword...
This is... the king's sword I inherited from Piao!
これは漂から受け継いだ王の剣だ！
ハァ… ハァ…
見てろ 壁！
Watch me, Bi!
うらぁ！
In both speed and strength, I have no equal!
（左慈）
速さも力も 俺にかなう者なし
信！
Xin!
Old man, it looks like so much blood rose to your head...
（信）
おっさん 頭に血が上り過ぎて―
気がつかなかったみたいだな
that you didn't notice...
あんた 壁に２回斬られて
速さも力も半減してたって
With the two cuts Bi gave you, your speed and strength were both reduced by half...
That was for Bi.
壁への落とし前だ
しっかり受け取れ
Take it in!
I... was...
（左慈）この俺が こんなガキに…
By... this brat...
Bastard... What... are you...?
貴様… 何者だ…
I'm Xin.
信だ
I did it, Bi.
やったぞ 壁
You won... Why're you crying?
（壁）勝利して…
ハッ…
（壁）なぜ泣くのだ？
Did someone close to you die or something?
誰か親しい人でも死んだのかな？
（信）壁！ 生きてたのか！
（壁）フフフッ…
Bi! You're alive?!
It looks like by drawing my hips back, the wound I took was a bit shallow.
腰が引けてた分 受けた傷も
ちょっと浅かったようだ
You damn bastard!
（信）てめえ この野郎！
びっくりさせやがって！
Don't scare me like that!
The warrior Tajif says "That man is alive. It's all right."
（バジオウ）戦士 タジフは―
“その男は生きている
大丈夫だ”と言っている
You're too late! Don't be telling that to me that now!
（信）遅(おせ)えよ！ 今ごろ言うな！
（笑い声）
どうやら終わったようですねえ
It seems it's over.
王と昌文君が信頼を寄せる…
The one the king and Changwenjun put their faith in...
I wonder just what kind of person they are...?
一体 どんな者なのでしょうねえ？
フフフフッ…
Everyone's really beat up...
（壁）皆 ボロボロだな
But to be up against Zuoci and such numbers...
しかし あの大人数と左慈を相手に
犠牲が２人とは―
and getting through with just two sacrifices, the Mountain People are beyond incredible.
山の民 恐るべしというところか
（信）まあ 大将さえ倒しちまえば
こんなもんよ
Well, if you can beat an enemy general, this is what happens.
（貂）それより 壁
寝てないで大丈夫なの？
Anyhow, Bi, are you gonna be all right with not resting?
He can't sleep after we've come this far!
（信）
ここまで来て 寝てられっかよ！
Right, Brother Bi?!
なあ？ 壁のあんちゃん
（壁）そのとおりだ…
Exactly...
When we get down this corridor...
この回廊を抜ければ
直ちに 本殿に着く
we'll be right at the inner palace.
And in there is the ringleader behind this all,
本殿には
この一件の首謀者 成蟜がいる
Chengjiao.
Do you hear me, Xin?!
（漂）いいな？ 信　託したぞ！
I'm entrusting this to you!
Are you ready, Xin?
（壁）覚悟はできてるか？ 信
（信）おうよ！
Hell yeah!
We'll defeat Chengjiao!
成蟜を討つぞ！
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
I won't cry
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
～♪
Preview
（信）な… 何だ？ てめえは！
Wh-What are you?!
Is this strange shadow a human? A beast?
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）異様な影は 人か獣か？
剣は無力と化した
Swords have become powerless.
The Roar of Lankai
End
Next time,
次回 “ランカイ吠(ほ)える”